[{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the most appropriate option nearest in meaning to the italicized or bold word\/phrase<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><b>The presence of the principal makes the students <em><u>ill at ease<\/u><\/em>.<\/b><\/p>","options":["easily ill","at ease","uncomfortable","sickly"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the most appropriate option nearest in meaning to the italicized or bold word\/phrase.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><b>In spite of the harsh realities at home, Tutu treats her studies with considerable <em><u>levity<\/u>.<\/em><\/b><\/p>","options":["lassitude","frivolity","seriousness","enthusiasm"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the most appropriate option opposite in meaning to the italicized word\/phrase..<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><b>I find <em><u>open-ended<\/u><\/em> questions more challenging in tests.<\/b><\/p>","options":["Fixed","Multiple-choice","Essay-type","Gap-completion"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the most appropriate option opposite in meaning to the italicized word\/phrase.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><b>Ojo\u2019s knowing smile <i><u>infuriated<\/u><\/i> his sister<\/b><\/p>","options":["Confused","Surprised","Annoyed","Pleased"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following highlighted <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">consonants<\/span> is pronounced differently from the others?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Fife","Off","Laugh","Of"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of these words has a <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">vowel<\/span> pronounced differently from the others?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Steak","Break","Leak","Strange"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the most appropriate option nearest in meaning to the italicized or bold word\/phrase.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong> People could not understand why a man of means should live a <u>s<\/u><em style=\"\"><u>partan<\/u><\/em> life.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["foreign","frugal","extravagant","flamboyant"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the most appropriate option nearest in meaning to the italicized word\/phrase.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong> My boss is an <u style=\"\"><i>exacting<\/i><\/u> taskmaster.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["hardworking","easygoing","demanding","cooperative"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the most appropriate option opposite in meaning to the italicized or bold word\/phrase.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong> The <u><em>explosive<\/em><\/u> growth in world population is partly due to improved healthcare.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Gradual","Sudden","Combustible","Dangerous"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the most appropriate option opposite in meaning to the italicized or bold word\/phrase.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>I would have enjoyed the novel but for its <em><u>convoluted<\/u><\/em> theme.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Simple","Complex","Immoral","Boring"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following highlighted <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">consonants<\/span> is pronounced differently from the others?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Chef","Chef","Chief","Ocean"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of these words has a <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">vowel<\/span> pronounced differently from the others?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Key","Quay","Steak","Greed"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the most appropriate option nearest in meaning to the italicized or bold word\/phrase.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>He was under pressure to <u style=\"\"><i>retract<\/i><\/u> his statement before the panel.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["reiterate","withdraw","assert","repeat"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the most appropriate option nearest in meaning to the italicized bold word\/phrase.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>His family wishes he would stop his <em><u>nefarious<\/u><\/em> activities.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["nocturnal","respectable","promiscuous","degenerate"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the most appropriate option opposite in meaning to the italicized or bold word\/phrase.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The nouveau riche tend to be <em><u>niggardly<\/u><\/em> in their ways.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Stingy","Miserly","Generous","Beggarly"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the most appropriate option nearest in meaning to the italicized word\/phrase. <\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Mrs Ojodu may be well-heeled but her dressing is often <i><u>tasteless<\/u><\/i><em>.<\/em><\/strong><\/p>","options":["vulgar","garish","refined","salty"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following highlighted <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">consonants<\/span> is pronounced differently from the others?<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["Tight","Thames","Though","Team"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following highlighted <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">consonants<\/span> is pronounced differently from the others?<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["Tight","Thames","Though","Team"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following highlighted <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">consonants<\/span> is pronounced differently from the others?<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["Tight","Thames","Though","Team"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of these words has a<em> vowel<\/em> pronounced differently from the others?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Gloom","Glum","Glue","Glume"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the most appropriate option nearest in meaning to the italicized or bold word\/phrase. <\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Practising law is not as lucrative as people <u style=\"\"><i>think<\/i><\/u>.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["know","understand","assume","consider"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the most appropriate option nearest in meaning to the italicized or bold word\/phrase.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong> The family puts up a brave face but their financial situation is <em><u>precarious<\/u>.<\/em><\/strong><\/p>","options":["buoyant","precious","unjustifiable","insecure"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the most appropriate option opposite in meaning to the italicized or bold word\/phrase.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong> As is usually the case when Tanus got involved, the discussion became<u> <em>animated<\/em>.<\/u><\/strong><\/p>","options":["Unruly","Specialized","Lively","Boring"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the most appropriate option opposite in meaning to the italicized or bold word\/phrase. <\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Gender-sensitivity is part of the new <i><u>political correctness<\/u><\/i>.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Inclusiveness","Naivet\u00e9","Insensitivity","Ideology"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following highlighted consonants is pronounced differently from the others?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["World","Whore","Hoar","Whole"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of these words<\/strong> has<strong> a vowel pronounced differently from the others?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Beast","Heft","Breast","Wealth"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the most appropriate option nearest in meaning to the italicized or bold word\/phrase.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong> The little village became more <em><span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">enchanting<\/span><\/em> at dusk.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["bewitched","accommodating","attractive","repulsive"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the most appropriate option nearest in meaning to the italicized or bold word\/phrase. <\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>More students are relying on <em><u>virtual<\/u><\/em> resources for study and entertainment.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["fundamental","righteous","automated","substantial"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the most appropriate option opposite in meaning to the italicized or bold word\/phrase.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>I wonder why her brother is<em> <u>indifferent<\/u><\/em> to her financial situation<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Interested in","Troubled by","Discouraged by","Filled with"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the most appropriate option opposite in meaning to the italicized or bold word\/phrase. <\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>I would have enjoyed the novel but for its <u><em>convoluted<\/em><\/u> theme.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Simple","Complex","Immoral","Boring"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following highlighted consonants is pronounced differently from the others?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["hiccough","Poppy","Cup","Tough"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of these words has a <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">vowel<\/span> pronounced differently from the others?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Height","High","Heist","Eight"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of these words has a <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">vowel<\/span> pronounced differently from the others?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Height","High","Heist","Eight"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the most appropriate option nearest in meaning to the italicized or bold word\/phrase. <\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>He was under pressure to <em><u>retract<\/u><\/em> his statement before the panel.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["reiterate","withdraw","assert","repeat"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the most appropriate option nearest in meaning to the italicized or bold word\/phrase. <\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>He was told to forget the <em><u>niceties<\/u><\/em> and go straight to his main point.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["specifics","politeness","greetings","nice things"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the most appropriate option opposite in meaning to the italicized or bold word\/phrase. <\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Our visit to the village was <em><u>nothing to write home about<\/u>.<\/em><\/strong><\/p>","options":["Not interesting","Not a home affair","Quite pleasant","Nobody's business"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the most appropriate option opposite in meaning to the italicized or bold word\/phrase. <\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Ojo\u2019s knowing smile <em><span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">infuriated<\/span><\/em> his sister<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Confused","Surprised","Annoyed","Pleased"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following highlighted <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">consonants<\/span> is pronounced differently from the<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>others?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Dung","Dog","Dagger","Agog"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of these words has a consonant pronounced differently from the others? <\/strong><\/p>","options":["Tough","Thames","Though","Team"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the most appropriate option opposite in meaning to the italicized or bold word\/phrase.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The government is making <u><em>concerted<\/em><\/u> efforts at improving the standard of living in rural areas.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Dissipated","Unconcerned","Uncooperative","Unsuccessful"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the most appropriate option opposite in meaning to the italicized or bold word\/phrase.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong> The politician\u2019s passionate appeal <em><u>doused<\/u><\/em> the tension<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Heightened","Smothered","Lifted","Drowned"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following highlighted <em>consonants<\/em> is pronounced differently from the others?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Dodge","Doge","Dogged","Drudge"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of these words has a <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">vowel<\/span> pronounced differently from the others?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Stead","Stealth","Steam","Bread"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the most appropriate option nearest in meaning to the italicized or bold word\/phrase.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The young groom is quite an <em><u>astute<\/u><\/em> businessman.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["acute","shrewd","honest","considerate"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the most appropriate option nearest in meaning to the italicized or bold word\/phrase.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The family puts up a brave face but their financial situation is <em><u>precarious<\/u><\/em>.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["buoyant","precious","unjustifiable","insecure"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the most appropriate option opposite in meaning to the italicized of bold word\/phrase.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The volume contains the <em><u>complete<\/u><\/em> works of Shakespeare.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Reprinted","Abridged","Edited","Selected"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the most appropriate option opposite in meaning to the italicized or bold word\/phrase.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>I find <em><u>open-ended<\/u><\/em> questions more challenging in tests.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Fixed","Multiple-choice","Essay-type","Gap-completion"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following highlighted <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">consonants<\/span> is pronounced differently from the others?<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["Chalet","Champion","Chagrin","Chaise"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of these words has a <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">vowel<\/span> pronounced differently from the others? <\/strong><\/p>","options":["Steak","Break","Leak","Strange"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"}]